PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- We actually do a lot of simulation at Pixar.
我们其实为皮克斯做很多模拟上的工作
Things like fire, water, and explosions
比如火啊 水啊 爆炸啊
are handled by the effects department.
这些都是有特效部门完成的
You can learn more about that in the effects lesson.
你会在特效那块课程里了解更多
The simulation department, who I work with,
我工作的模拟部门
handles any motion attached to the characters at Pixar,
是负责所有附着于角色的物体的运动
like clothing and hair.
比如布料和毛发
But we can't move every hair
但我们不可能手动地
on a Pixar character's head by hand,
移动角色头上的每一根头发
that would drive our animators crazy.
那样我们的动画师就疯了
Instead, we use Physics and Computer Programming.
取而代之的，我们借助计算机和程序来实现
In this lesson, you'll learn how to
在这课中 你将学到我们
simulate hair the same way we did for Merida
是如何模拟merida的头发的
in the movie "Brave".
在电影brave中
Here is an example of a shot of Merida
有这样一个merida的镜头
that the simulation department got
当时就从动画部门那儿
from the animation department
交到了我们手上
on the film "Brave".
负责这个片子的部门
The animators have created the main action in the scene
动画师已经完成了角色的动作
and now it's our job to fill in the missing details
现在我们要来添加失去的细节
such as the motion of cloth and hair.
这就是衣服和头发
Everything we do begins with modeling the problem
要做一件事 就要先找到
we want to solve.
什么问题是我们要解决的
In this case, we need a physical model
这里我们需要一个
of Merida's curly hair.
merida头发的物理模型
So let's begin with the very basics.
让我们从基础开始
What should our model of hair look like?
我们的头发模型应该是怎样的
Well, hair is kind of like a mop,
你看 头发其实就像一个拖把
just a bunch of strings.
就是一捆线
But strings are actually quite complex
但这玩儿也是很难用数学模型来模拟的
to model mathematically because they are so bendy.
因为它们是这么有韧性
Modeling them requires a lot of computational power
对他进行数学建模需要需要很多运算能力
due to all the calculations involved.
正因为这么多的计算会介入
This is why we are always looking for ways
所以我们才要找一个方法
to simplify our models.
来优化我们建立的模型
For example, we could take a bunch of paper clips
比如我们可以简化成用一束纸片
to model a strand of hair.
来作为头发的模型
We first draw a series of line segments
我们首先画出一系列线段
connected to particles, like this.
然后像这样连接到粒子
The computer needs to calculate the positions
计算机需要运算
of these particles.
这些粒子的位置
But first we need to describe what forces
但首先我们要定义在它们上面
are acting on them.
有哪些力在作用
In the real world, each particle is affected
在真实世界里 所有粒子
by three forces.
都由三个力作用
The force of gravity,
重力
and the forces from neighboring connections, like this.
万有引力 和牵引力
Next step, I have an interactive program
下一步 我有一个交互程序
for you to see this in action.
来让你看看这个作用
You can adjust the following parameters:
你可以调节以下这些数据
size of each segment, number of segments per hair,
调整每个线段的长度 设置每个头发（被分割成的）线段的数量
number of hairs, and the force of gravity.
头发的数量和重力
Explore these parameters to see what kinds
不断实验不同的参数来看看
of looks you can come up with.
哪种是你想要的效果
Have fun. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
祝你愉快